More excitement as the finalists come in for the women's floor.
For me, General Mastisensu said this is the last event for the artistic because it's been a heck of a ride.
We've had such wonderful competitions, such great champions.
It's been amazing.
I always think about gymnastics.
I've had so many different competitions, the teams, the all-around.
Then you should the event finals.
It goes so fast.
These athletes have worked so long for this.
It's two and a half week period.
We put it all on the line and this is a tremendous lineup on the floor exercise.
Tonight we've bought the past World Champion from 2011, from 2010, past Olympic champions.
2008 and 2004.
That's probably the most surprising thing about it.
Two Romanians, per knock on his baza.
Olympic champions, both of them, on four in our weight and still here.
World champions in there.
Congratulations.
Taken Akmanateva.
Congratulations to the American.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Congratulations to the American.
Congratulations to the World Champion.
Congratulations to the worldwide.
representative Italy by the municipality ofatura.
hatch personnage
represent.
So we have two competitors from the Russian Federation, two from the USA, two from Romania.
The Interlopers, if you like, are from Australia and Italy, but Lauren Mitchell, a former world
champion, Vanessa Ferrari, a former world all around champion.
So everybody brings serious credibility to this final, Shannon, and what you got feeling
about how it might go.
I'm afraid to gas it anymore.
I shouldn't quit your own spot, so I haven't done that before, and I shouldn't do it with the last one.
You just sit back and enjoy it. That's what we should do, because we've been surprised every time.
By the quality of performances, sometimes the favourites have come through and sometimes not,
but we've always been given a treat. And it starts right now with Kissimia, I find a saver.
What we hope for is a clean competition where everyone hits, and then we see how they stack up.
World champion 2011, Ole Missumann, opening up huge double-layout, fighting to stay in bounds.
Flag goes up.
Whip whip, total full beautiful.
That's it.
That's it. That's a beautiful trip, best to watch.
I'm combining artistry a lot with powerful top one.
When it happens, our bounds again.
To both the talent she went out with only one foot or two, one foot is one tenth, two feet is three tenths of a deduction.
Finishing up her Olympics.
A couple of bid deductions there with the steps out of bounds.
I think that explains it.
A few extra points.
Finishing up her Olympics.
A couple of bid deductions there with the steps out of bounds.
I think that explains it.
A neutral expression as she leaves the floor.
It wasn't quite what she wanted for a saver who qualified for best with 4833.
Touch and go the first out of bounds.
And she really looked like she was going to hold on to it.
Sign of, just with that right little toe.
That's all it takes.
And this one way out, almost landing out of bounds very close.
We might throw out the floor competition, men and women, it's a springy one.
And Tom's even slippery.
That's what the athletes have been telling us.
It's kind of hard throughout but springy on the diagonal where you tumble.
And that can throw you away out of bounds.
And that's all we need now.
Well, respectable but not likely to be middle winning.
15, 5, 6, 6.
Let's see how it holds up.
And just don't know.
Jordan Weaver.
All around the world champion.
From 2011 she has become a crowd favorite.
Nearly missed an opportunity for the all-around competition.
Open to the huge pass.
Double-tasting, double-back.
Little bounds on that landing but she managed to stay in bounds.
Half the triple and she's out as well.
Jordan has worked so hard but such a great deal of time and flexibility.
With dance over the years.
Really trying to match how well she does at an hour area on the top of her.
The top of the top of the top.
This double and this leaves.
Just as important as all of the top of the top.
The solid performance began just as the landings sink out of bounds.
Just to come all the steps here and there.
The field for the women's floor really had to wait quite a while since this final session began to have the chance to perform.
That's right.
What they do is they'll warm up in the back off of the podium while the men are competing.
They're against right here.
You can see.
I'm trying to hold on to that landing.
Right here.
She'll go one and a half.
Right through to a triple fall.
And that leap just put her out.
She got a little bit more horizontal movement backwards than she wanted.
I'm going to go a little bit more vertical.
See these athletes doing lots of jumps out of their tumbling passes.
I hope with that landing you no longer can do the lunge out.
You have to stick the landing or do a jump out.
So when the Weber score 45.6 for I think a saver.
The second competitor.
The American funny raceman is next.
She's encouraging her.
She waits for her own score.
Weber was 14.66 during the qualification round.
She's a good player.
Hold up doesn't seem to be with those two judges.
They're looking around.
Is that what they finished to whatever they need to do?
Never easy for the next competitor.
Here's another look at the first tumbling pass.
Two twists, two flips before she hits the ground.
So much power goes into that move.
You can see the spring and the give and the floor during that slow motion replay.
The 14.5 is in the Jordan Reba.
Slides in behind.
I think we've seen the winning performance yet.
And the number one qualify for the floor final with a 15.325.
She has a huge opening tumbling pass.
Such a strong steady competitor.
I don't know how twist.
Punch double Arabian.
Punch layout and nails it.
She's back, tight double Arabian.
Another clean landing.
Already has a gold in the team.
Bronze in the beam.
I don't triple twist.
She's got a wet pass left.
Well, the pad loved it.
Good reason.
That is a performance debate in the floor final.
She's got a good feeling about the first time.
Her enormous 6.5 star value pops the field.
I had to think of a mistake in there.
It was very clean and impressive.
The landing was very clean.
The US program coordinator said it's just proof that hard work pays off.
The most hard working dedicated athlete throughout the year.
That's high praise.
The luckier you get, the more you get.
The performance deserves a high market.
Not touted as the one coming in.
She could be the US athlete that walks away with three medals from these games.
She was 15-3-2-5 in the qualification.
15-6 here.
She's over a four-marque higher than Afuna Saiva and Weber.
Dare I say, I think that's the highest score that we've seen in women's floor exercise.
Not just today overall.
That's an amazing contribution to make to the sport.
It's an overwhelming achievement.
We've got five to come.
This woman here, Olympic champion on this event in 2004.
Gorgeous opening double layout.
Back with whip to a pipe full in.
Right to a back pipe.
Honour is so calm and collected through competition.
She actually had her hands lift during this past the triple fold or qualification.
Maintained her proposal and made it into the final round.
Another great landing.
She gives the judges' fever with this performance.
It's unbelievable if she can keep her going to the end.
Maint puts some pressure on Ryzen.
A pipe to finish.
That's her best.
That was a terrific performance.
And yet again, in a final, we're seeing athletes step up.
And a little better than their qualifying score.
Ryzen and 15-6 are...
I don't know if anyone can get near it, but Pino is certainly trying.
This is going to be tied.
This was a terrific performance from Catalina Ponoir.
But no one else in the field has the difficulty value of Razeman.
But these landings were spot on.
And it's just tremendous to see Catalina out there.
Heating at this high of level still vying for Olympic medals.
Eight years after she did so in 2004.
14.6 during the qualification round, which she had a slight mistake.
She's 25, later this month.
Maybe expect this to be her last Olympics.
And a 15-2 for Pinoir is a great score, much better than qualifying.
But she can't get near Razeman in the second place.
And we hear booze from the audience by Zai 6.2 in difficulty value.
Compared to a 6.5 for Ali Razeman.
It goes a great score.
That was Pinoir's highest score, beautiful routine.
And should keep her in silver.
Lauren Mitchell, former World Champion on floor from 2010.
I remember the Olympics shot injured with an abdominal strain.
But she's had a few days extra to get that right.
Let's see what she can do here.
Lauren dealing with not only the abdominal strain,
which affects everything that you do, but the tear in her shoulders as well as...
...a little bit of strength.
Wins to double Arabian, beautiful opening pass.
Coming back, high-follet.
What is it's low on that jump out?
It's got the sun.
Two and a half bunch left.
This is coming up a tad short.
It'll be a very minor deduction.
Another great performance.
We're seeing a few.
Lauren Mitchell sitting to become the first Australian...
...to get a medal in Nepper out of final.
But the competition's so hot, Shannon.
I don't know if she can do it.
It is so tough and Lord is accustomed to making history.
Becoming Australia's first female gymnast.
When a world championship event final in this event,
huge opening pass whipped directly to a double Arabian.
Nice, sadly, but the end.
She comes from Perth in Western Australia.
There's a great gymnastics program there.
Under the Western Australian Institute of Sport.
She really had a couple of years troubled by injury.
So the makeup final here.
And a great performance from her.
Came in with 14.833 during the qualification round.
Put her in the fifth position coming into this competition.
I'm going to have to finish the lead with this is the end of her gymnastics career.
It might be though.
And we'll see if it's one to remember alongside a medal.
It's just Athens Ava.
She needs high 14.
Sorry, she's right.
And she could place in the high 14.
1833 and she has equal data again tonight.
The 4833 from Mitchell into third position ahead of Athens Ava and Weeber.
1333 very good performances to come from Ferrari,
Mr. Fiener and his buster, Italy, Russia and Romania.
Still to come.
The
Athens of the 2006 world all around champion.
And she's coming into tonight's final on floor exercise in third position.
Opening up huge double double.
Going for her exciting choice of attire as well as her power.
Nice height on the mountain pass.
The massive host of pretty high star value coming in with a 6.2
And a great finish.
But when this is a Ferrari's already made history for Italian gymnastics,
15 year olds who won that world all around Toronto.
I don't know if she can do something there.
Maybe in the Italian media going crazy for it as they've got in the past.
When you think of gymnastics being the young woman's sport and yet we're seeing a lot of these two time Olympians.
Even four time world champion, these competitors in the world champions.
It seems like there's a little bit more longevity in the sport these days.
This was a great routine.
Just a couple of minor mistakes on landings a little bit in the leap area.
But again she has a pretty good start value with 6.2.
And she's hovering typically around a 14.9, 14.866 here at the Games.
14.833 is the Mark Lauren Mitchell holes third position at the moment.
So Ferrari can certainly get me that.
I can see them popping away.
You know how hard they're working for that 90 seconds chance.
It really is incredible.
I mean there's so much tumbling that you have to pack in to that 90 seconds.
You really don't have that much time to breathe.
I'm just making a sweat this one out for on Ferrari's behalf.
I'm going to look at her performance.
Oh no.
The crowd is getting a little antsy.
That is serious hand injury in 2005.
Four screws pressed in the hand.
That's surgery.
That's some kind of stories that I'm coming at all.
And Ferrari moves into third place with a 14.9 so there will be no historic metal for Lauren Mitchell but maybe for Ferrari.
Still two performances to come though.
I'm yeah, Mr. Fina who has already won gold on uneven bars.
Third and the all around.
Second and the tenth.
So she's got the full set.
Gold Silver bronze.
Huge opening.
Perfectly vertical.
Two and a half clutchful.
She has been such a joy to watch.
Certainly not expected to take the gold on uneven bars and paint through.
Exactly the right time.
We mentioned her injury.
Major ACL tear.
Just 18 months ago.
It's so important what you think about.
The lower exercise and the pounding of your mistakes.
The lower exercise and the lower exercise.
Finished up triple full.
That was a tripping performance.
A couple little errors here and there.
I'm going to go on some of the landing and the
triple twizz so those execution deductions are going to add up.
The performance and raise one is almost intimidating.
Not the final was in timidator.
She came out with a 15-2 and the crowd thought it should have been more
but for the rest of the field something in the mid 15s is feels like it's unachievable.
It really is incredible to watch and it kind of makes it a race for silver.
Sandra's Basia who is the last competitor could get there with the
perfect routine and in this from most most of the time.
Terrific opening tumbling pass.
Again you see just a little bit of a flicker in the knees on some of these tumbling runs.
Comes in with a 15.9 and difficulty value from the qualification round.
So the first barrier to get past is 14.9.
That is Ferrari in the bronze medal position.
Ponawer on 15-2.
Rasmussen 15-6.
I think with the 13, I'm just looking into that bronze medal position
would certainly not be unheard of.
She consistently places a mid to high 14s.
It's in this completes and completes.
They know their competition is over.
Mr. Fiener 14-9 also but gets it on execution ahead of Ferrari.
Wow.
Again the tie break rules are applied to the scores and Ferrari looking disconsolate.
It will be academic if this pass comes up and gets into the medals as well.
Ponawer is sitting in second because she lost out on the tie break when it was applied in the bean.
That's right.
Allie Rasmussen, Pelleena Ponawer, good for medals.
Just a matter of what color and Sandra is Basia taking the gold on vault in a huge upset.
Really performing terrifically.
Last routine, autistic gymnastics 2012.
Sandra is Basia is the reigning Olympic champion on this event.
The orange is open to pass.
She is so clean on these landings.
Judges watching the drop of that heel make sure those turns are completed 360 degrees.
The orange is open to pass.
Oh, and big issue there on the last talent pass.
It was such a gorgeous routine.
What a shame for Sandra is Basia but that is a really significant deduction.
We talk about the timing on those bounding moves.
Allie Rasmussen knows she has the gold.
She is such a tough break for her.
She could have meddled.
Absolutely.
She would have had one of the medals.
Otherwise, terrific performance.
Perfect landing.
She still has the gold.
This is where the difficulty was.
The landing passes are very difficult because you have to have the timing just right.
She went wrong.
The sport did not get the right punch for that second move.
She was a good player.
Another look at Isbasa not going home empty handed.
She has the gold on vault.
Fortunately, Flore was not working for her tonight.
A 13, 333 for Isbasa.
She was heavily penalized.
She was a good player.
She had a good location.
She always had her reading team pay for her performance line for the bronze medal.
For Graseman, one of the truly great performances on Flore,
seen anywhere any time.
She has been so steady, so consistent, such a hard worker.
was fourth in the all around.
Please show your appreciation for the firm itself.
It's easy, O'Rea.
And bronze, of course, on the bean.
So quite a haul for Ali Roseman.
The US picks up their third gold medal.
An alfinish second behind China in the artistic gymnastics
medal table.
China with four gold, three silver,
and the bronze for eight medals, USA 312.
Two makes six.
And that up for myself, then.
I can still count to six.
That's encouraging.
And the Russian Federation.
Japan, Romania, Hungary, Brazil,
Republic of Korea, the Netherlands,
and all with gold medals.
Nine nations actually collecting gold medals.
So it's great to see it spread around at that extent.
You read it.
You're all in the history.
So just one more medal presentation to come.
And it's this four exercise final.
Three of the strongest nations in the sport.
The US and Russia in that order.
Raised in colonel and musterfanner.
I can stay with us for the medals shortly.
It confirms it for you.
By point four, Ali Razeman takes the gold ahead of Ketalina Pono,
USA Romania, and third, Ali and Miss Daphina.
Split on the tie-breaker of the execution scores
with Vanessa Ferrari.
Miss Daphina gets the bronze,
Laura Mitchell of Australia,
Miss Senni Affanisaba,
the Russian Federation in Jordan,
Weaver, USA, and Sandra Bistassa.
Romania.
And last final.